Hello everyone, a very warm welcome to all of you.
You are watching You The Real. I am your
own personal advisor Amitraj Sharma. In today's
video, we will learn about ICICI Potential Life
's Signature Pension Plan.
But before that, we would like to inform you
that a real plan is subject to market risk.
Any money you invest here is subject to
market-related risk.
ICICI Potential Signature Pension Plan is a
market-based retirement solution. If you
want to accumulate a corpus for your retirement by investing in the market, so that you want to
build such a corpus from which you can get a
regular guaranteed pension in the future, then you
invest money in this type of plan where
you also manage the risk. We will
understand further how the benefits work. Now
we will learn about the eligibility criteria of ICICI Potential Life's
Signature Pension Plan. The
age limit for taking the plan is minimum 18
years and maximum 65 years. People up to the age of 65 years
can take this plan. The vesting age limit is
minimum 60 years.  80 years old,
right? When it comes to the premium payment
term, if you choose a premium payment term of five to nine years, the
minimum premium
limit is ₹1 lakh annually. If the premium
payment term is 10 to 15 years, then the
minimum premium limit is ₹
60,000. If you want to pay a one-time premium and
choose the single premium option, the minimum premium limit will be
₹1 lakh. The minimum policy term will be
either 20 years or 80 years. You can
subtract your entry age from the plan,
right. This will be the
minimum policy term. The maximum policy term is
62 years. You can
also get the option of a top-up premium in this plan.
Let's learn about the benefits of ICICI
Potential Life's Signature Pension Plan.
First, let's
talk about the death benefit. Since this is
a pension-targeting plan,
what will happen to the fund value if the life cover age is not met?  If a
comparison is made, 105% of the
premium paid till the date of death will be taken and
whichever is
higher will be the death benefit. Now the
nominee will have the choice to either
take the complete death benefit as lump sum or he can
take immediate or deferred annuity pension plan. Deferred at
annuity means pension only. You can take it from ICICI or
from someone else, it
depends on them. The
partial withdrawal limit for the nominee is the same,
first of all the locking period should be complete.
Locking period means that
5 years of the policy should be completed. The minimum partial
withdrawal limit is ₹5000000. You will
not be able to withdraw for the first time. When
can you withdraw for higher education of your children,
for their marriage or for treatment of any critical illness
you have suffered or for
building the first house of your life
or for your self development or
You are improving your skills or
you have started a startup and need money for it.
In that case, the minimum limit for top-up premium is
₹5000000. The maximum
lump sum amount you can invest in the
rest is ₹1000000. The pension amount and the
rate of pension will be known in that seed. When this much corpus is
accumulated, the pension will go into the pension fund. This means that the
pension will be charged on the annual premium of the single life plan. The
return of purchase price is ₹5000000. Let us
now know about the charges of ICICI Potential Life
's Signature Pension Plan. The
first is the policy administration
charge of 0.2% of the annual premium.
In case of single premium, the
limit is ₹5000000. The premium
allocation charge, which is levied
in case of limited premium, will be ₹
4% of the premium paid. The
policy discontinuation charge can be levied from ₹1
to ₹100 depending on the
year in which you
discontinued the policy and the premium you paid.
Now you can turn the video on full screen and you will
also know about the fund options. The
name of the first fund here is Pension
Multi Cap Growth Fund. The company launched this fund on
January 11, 2010. From January 11,
2010 till now,
it has had an average rate of return of 10.9%. The second fund
here is Pension Opportunity Fund. Pension
Opportunity Fund was also launched on January 11, 2010.
From January 11, 2010 till now, it has had an
average rate of return of 11.9%. The
Blue Chip Fund was launched by the company on January 11, 2010
and the Pension Blue Chip Fund has
given a rate of return of around 10% from January 11, 2010 till now. This is the average rate of
return which keeps increasing or decreasing with time
as per the performance of the fund. The
company also launched Pension Multi Cap Balanced Fund on
January 11, 2010. From then till
now, the average rate of return has been  The
company also launched the Pension Income Fund on
January 11, 2010, which was 9.24%. The
average rate of return has been 7.81%.
You can get this information on their website,
I have taken it from there, I am not telling anything from my own. The
company launched the Pension India Growth Fund
on August 30, 2024, and since then
its return has been more than 7% in negative,
7.36%, meaning
right in minus. The company launched the Pension Balance Fund on
August 30, 2024, and from August 30, 2024 till
now, its
average rate of return has been 0.90% in minus. The Pension Money
Market Fund was launched on January 11, 2010, and since then, the
average rate of return has been 6.85%. The
fund management chart that will be applied on this fund will charge
0.75% of the annual average fund value. With all other fund
options, a
fund management charge of 1.35% of the annual average fund value will be levied.
Now we will watch the full video.  We will do it on the screen
because there is no benefit in doing calculations
because whatever the fund performance is,
that is what we will get. So let us understand the illustration
which is given in the brochure. Here the
age taken is 40 years. An annual premium of ₹ lakh is being paid
for 15 years and we want to retire at the age of 60 years, that is, a
20 year term is being taken.
Now a positive term of 20 years is being taken. If we are
paying for 15 years, then we will
pay ₹ lakh at the rate of ₹ lakh and
100% of the money is being invested here in Pension India Growth Fund. So the
brochure says that if the rate of return is around 8%, then a
corpus of ₹ 6631897 can be
created. If the rate of return is 4%, then ₹
9848824365, only then the
rate will be decided. Rest,
some information about this plan is also left, it is
important for you to know that which I will tell you in the next part,
but one  Overall, I have given you an overview
because the main thing in this type of plan is
eligibility criteria
and fund performance, hence I have told you in this video itself,
you will get the idea,
thank you, all of you take care of yourselves and do
like and share the video
because that is what gives motivation to
work for you, thank you.